惠特妮·威廉姆斯  2我岁  在E号线上
Whitney Williams, 22. She went into convulsions
突然抽搐  随后一直时醒时昏
on the "E" Train... in and out of consciousness ever since.
查下全血细胞计数和心电图  身上发现毒品了吗
I want a cbc and an ekg. Any sign of drugs on her?
没有  但她曾说是有人害了她
Nothing. But at one point, she said someone did this to her.
惠特妮  能告诉我是怎么回事吗
Whitney, can you tell me what happened?
德蒙贝克
Diamondback.
她在抽搐  注入4毫克安定文
She's seizing. Push 4 milligrams Ativan.
朋友们  感谢大家这么短的时间内能赶到
Friends, thank you for coming on such short notice.
这种时候  会让我想到莎士比亚
Well, it's times like these I'm reminded of Shakespeare,
他曾写"星辰不是..."
who wrote, "It's not in the stars..."
他还写过"简略才是智慧的灵魂"
Ah, ah, ah, he also said, "Brevity is the soul of wit."
赶紧说吧  亲爱的
So get to it, darling.
好的
Uh, okay.
我们刚从汉普顿斯回来
We just returned from the Hamptons, and...
-我们结婚了  -我们结婚了
- We got married! - We got married!
好诶
Yes!
-你们为什么这样  -好过分
- W-why did you do that? - You guys suck.
-等等  -你们...
- Hold... hold up. - You cou--
不不不
No, no, no, no, no...
你们结婚居然没请我们去
You guys jumped the broom and didn't invite us?
-实在是一时兴起决定的  -兴起
- It was spur-of-the-moment. - Spur.
真是太美了
Oh, and it was perfection.
你们真该去的
I mean, you should have been there.
充满激情和爱
It was fire and love.
而且还有鸽子...
And at one point, there were all these doves...
-飞如天...  -奶奶  奶奶
- that just soared into the... - Gram, gram...
-我们就让他们更难受了  -际...
- Maybe we don't rub it in. - into the...
-我们再去给你们拿一杯吧  -好的
- Let's go get you another drink. - Oh. Drink. Okay.
来吧
Come on.
拿着这个
Hold this.
我可是你的伴娘
I am your maid of honor.
我都一个月没吃碳水化合物了
I haven't had a carb in months,
就怕我还得再穿一次礼服
just in case I had to put that damn dress back on.
-你看上去好棒  -少拍马了
- And you look great. - Save the flattery.
凯特  你欠我晚饭
Kate, you owe me dinner.
我选餐馆
I'm picking the restaurant,
我们要把所有甜点都点齐了
and we're ordering all the desserts.
好
Okay.
你结婚了啊
Oh, girl, you're married!
过来
Come here!
伙计们
Guys.
拜托
Guys, come on.
不要  我们期待这事
No. We were really looking forward to this
可很久了  卡塞尔
for a long time, too, Castle.
我们还准备了讲话
We had a speech prepared and everything.
我们还写了歌
Ohh, plus, we wrote that song.
-是啊  -真假的  你们还写歌了
- Yeah. - Seriously, you wrote a song?
我们打算办个婚宴
We're... we're planning a little reception.
你们可以在婚宴上唱啊
You guys could do the song at the reception.
-才不给你唱  -你的机会过去了
- No song for you. - You had your chance.
伙计们  庆祝得先放放了
Guys...we're gonna have to cut the celebration short.
有凶杀案
There's been a murder.
是吗  我们没接到通知啊
Really? We didn't get that call.
又没受人邀请  干杯
Once again, not invited. Cheers.
好吧
Fine.
分局见
We'll meet you at the precinct.
本可能更糟的
Well, it could have been worse.
还是可能更糟啊
It still might be.
谁知道他们现在在怎么折腾我们家啊
I mean, who knows what they're doing to our place right now?
你听到你说什么了吗
You hear what you just said?
"我们家"  我们诶  我们结婚了
"Our place." Our. We're married.
我们结婚了  我们成功了  卡塞尔太太
We're married. We did it, Mrs. Castle!
是啊  贝克特先生
We certainly did, Mr. Beckett.
不过这可不是
Although this arguably isn't
最浪漫的婚后活动
the most romantic post-wedding activity.
或许也很合适  考虑到我们是怎么认识的
Or perhaps it's fitting, considering how we met.
但你说得对  得考虑蜜月了
But you bring up an excellent point... the honeymoon.
是啊  关于去异国岛屿度假
Yes. About the exotic island getaway...
那个得等等了
I-it's gonna have to wait.
-为什么  -因为你失踪的时候
- Why? - Because when you went missing,
我把我的假期都用来找你了
I used up all of my vacation days looking for you.
那没有蜜月了
So no honeymoon.
一段日子内是不行了
Mm, not for a while, I'm afraid.
没有迈代鸡尾酒  我们只有杀人案
So instead of Mai Tais... we get murder.
好啊
Great.
这挺好的
Nah, it'll be great.
惠特妮·威廉姆斯
Whitney Williams.
先是抽搐  随后心脏停搏
She went into convulsions, then cardiac arrest.
我们没能救活她
We couldn't bring her back.
她的遗言是德蒙贝克
And her last words were "Diamondback"?
-那是什么  -不知道
- What does that mean? - I have no idea.
她自称是被人谋害
And she believed that she was a victim of foul play.
是的  我也这么认为
Yes, and so do I.
我们进行了血检
We ran a full blood work-up,
检测到了高剂量的地高辛
and it came back with high traces of digoxin.
那是心脏药物
Oh, that's a heart medication.
从毛地黄中萃取的
Derived from the foxglove plant.
据我们的尸检官称
According to our pathologist,
这是未提纯的地高辛  直接从植物中提取的
this was un-purified digoxin, taken directly from the plant.
-是致命剂量  -她是被毒死的
- It's lethal. - So she was poisoned.
能知道她摄入毛地黄有多久了吗
A-any way to tell how long ago she ingested the foxglove?
我们估计为10到14小时
We're estimating 10 to 14 hours.
你联系她亲属了吗
Have you contacted the next of kin?
我觉得你们会想来处理这事
I thought you would want to handle that.
这是她的紧急情况卡
This is her in-case-of-emergency card.
多谢前来达格玛先生和太太
Thanks for coming in, Mr. And Mrs. Dagmar.
她妈妈过世后  我们应该是
Well, since her mom passed, I suppose
惠特妮最接近亲人的人了
we're the closest thing to family that Whitney has.
她是我们第一个达格玛奖学金获得者
She was our first Dagmar scholar.
那是什么
Dagmar scholar?
我们为穷苦孩子提供资金
We sponsor disadvantaged children,
送他们去好学校
send them to the finest schools.
下毒是在10到14小时之前
The poisoning occurred between 10 and 14 hours ago.
你们知道惠特妮当时在哪里
Do you happen to know where Whitney was
或者跟谁在一起吗
or who she was with at the time?
不知道
No.
我们最后一次见她是一周前
The last time we saw her was a week ago
她来吃晚饭
when she came over for supper.
她提到她跟谁有矛盾了吗
Did she mention if she was having problems with anyone,
也许在工作上
Perhaps at work?
她说过要休息下
She did say she was going to
-暂时不做实习了   -你知道原因吗
- take some time off from her internship. - Do you know why?
她妈妈最近去世了
Her mother's death was recent.
惠特妮说需要点时间来平复心灵的创伤
Whitney said she needed some time to get over the loss.
德蒙贝克这词  你们听过吗
Does the word "Diamondback" mean anything to either of you?
-没有  -我想没有
- No. - No, I'm afraid not.
德蒙贝克
Okay. "Diamondback."
反复斟酌后
I've whittled it down to
我猜测德蒙贝克可能有三种含义
three possibilities as to what that means
同时能够解释为何惠特妮死前会说这个
and why Whitney would utter it with her dying breath.
我相信每一种都很有说服力
And I'm sure that none of them will be a waste of my time.
可能性一  它是一个地下
Possibility number one -- it's the password
格斗俱乐部的暗号
for a murderous underground snake-handling fight club.
诚然  也许不是这个意思
Granted, that's probably not what it means,
但这可能成为我妮基·希特系列下本书的创意
but it might be the basis for my next Nikki Heat novel.
可能性二  她是被
Possibility number two -- she was killed
漫威漫画人物杀害  其特殊能力
by the marvel character diamondback, whose special skill
是投射菱形毒刺
was throwing diamond-shaped spikes filled with poison.
可能性三
Third possibility
是亚利桑那州一家度假农场
It's a dude ranch in Arizona.
达格玛夫妇那里毫无结果  但我们找到一封
We struck out with the Dagmars, but we found an e-mail
发自德蒙贝克老西部度假村的住宿确认邮件
to Whitney from a diamondback old west ranch
惠特妮在牧场工人宿舍14号房定了2周住宿
confirming a two-week stay in bunkhouse number 14.
老西部农场度假村  这就是我说的可能性三
Old west dude ranch. That's my number three.
我刚要说呢  干得好  兄弟们
That's exactly what I was gonna say. Good work, boys.
你还是逊毙了
You still suck.
你还欠我们伴郎服的租赁费呢
And you owe us for those tuxedo rentals.
她去亚利桑那度了两周假
So, she was on vacation in Arizona for two weeks?
-是的  -有人和她一起吗
- Yep.  - She go with anyone?
没有  但这种城市人乡村体验的事情
No, but it looks like the whole "City slickers" cowboy thing
显然不太适合她
didn't really agree with her.
惠特妮缩减了她的行程
Whitney cut her trip short.
只在那待了三天
After only three days there,
她就把机票改签了
she paid for a last-minute ticket change
于今早8点飞往菲尼克斯
from 8. a.m flight out of Phoenix this morning.
今早  所以她是在亚利桑那当地时间
This morning? So she was poisoned in Arizona
凌晨1点至5点间被下毒的
somewhere between 1:00 to 5:00 a.m. local time.
所有证据显示她离开的很匆忙
And all indications are that she left in a big hurry.
她甚至忘了归还宿舍的钥匙
She even forgot to turn in her bunkhouse key.
我需要那个地方所有的资料
Okay, I need every detail we can get on that place.
据网上说
Well, according to this,
德蒙贝克老西部农场是一个充满历史感的度假胜地
"Diamondback old west ranch is a living history resort
服务员和客人均着老式的西部服装
"Where both staff and guests dress in old west attire
体验牛仔的生活
and engage in cowboy activities."
听起来很不错
This sounds pretty cool!
不  你想想惠特妮是在那里被毒死的
Or not, considering Whitney might have been poisoned there.
等等  如果惠特妮是今日乘机返回的话
Wait a minute -- if Whitney flew back today,
那她毒发的时候应该坐在
then she was coming in on the train from JFK
从肯尼迪机场出发的地铁上
when she had that seizure.
在医院我们只找到了她的钱包
But the only personal effect that we found at the hospital
所以她的行李去哪了
was her purse, so where is her luggage?
也许救护队带走她时  落在地铁上了
Maybe it was left in the subway when the medics took her.
如果是在农场被下毒的
Well, if something happened at that ranch,
那她的行李里也许会留下证据
there might be evidence of it in her suitcases.
-我会去查的   -我去查查她的账单
- I'll look into it.  - And I'll keep digging in her financials.
也许在亚利桑那她还去过别的地方
Maybe there's somewhere else she went in Arizona.
我会联系当地的治安官
And I'll touch base with the local sheriff
-寻求合作调查  -谢了  伙计
- and coordinate with him on the investigation. - Thanks, big boy.
警探  在我看来
Look, detective the way I see it,
这事不在亚利桑那的管辖范围
This is not an Arizona matter.
治安官  我们有证据
Sheriff, we have evidence
证明惠特妮是在你的管辖区内被下毒的
that Whitney was poisoned in your jurisdiction.
不  你只是猜测罢了
No, what you have is speculation.
她可能是在飞机上或者机场被下毒的
She could have been poisoned on the plane or at the airport.
而且我也不知道从哪开始调查
Hell, I wouldn't know where to begin.
我来告诉你
Well, I-I'm telling you where to begin --
德蒙贝克老西部农场
Diamondback old west ranch.
警探  你要明白  那个度假村
Detective, you got to understand. That resort --
可是我们旅游小镇的命根子
That's the lifeblood of our little tourist town.
-所以这涉及到政治了  -不  是私人感情
- So this is political.  - No, it's personal.
听着  这里有我一起长大的朋友
Look, I've got people here -- folks I grew up with --
我不能平白无故地打扰人家的生意
and I can't justo in and disrupt business
除非你有确实的证据
until there's some concrete proof.
非常遗憾  没有当地治安官的合作
I'm sorry. Without the sheriff's cooperation,
我们能做的十分有限
there's only so much we can do.
所以我们就让凶手逍遥法外了吗
So we're just gonna let him get away with this?
就像我们不计较
Kind of like how we let you get away
你们不请我们去婚礼一样
with not inviting us to the wedding?
至少你们被邀去祝酒了
Well, at least you were invited to the champagne toast.
抱歉  长官
Uh... sorry, sir.
不不  我确定这是卡塞尔先生的错
Oh, no, no, no. I'm sure it was Mr. Castle's fault.
关于案子  我联络联邦局
Now, regarding the case, I'll call the feds
看他们能否为我们说说情
and see if they can intercede on our behalf.
长官  那可得好几周呢
Sir, that could take weeks.
到那时什么证据证人都没了
By then, any evidence or witnesses could be long gone.
长官  我查了惠特妮的消费记录
Uh, excuse me, sir, I checked Whitney's financials.
她今早叫了的士
She used a car service
送她去亚利桑那的机场
to get to the airport in Arizona this morning.
我跟司机谈过了
And I spoke with the driver.
他说她离开农场时心情很沮丧
He said she seemed upset when she left the ranch.
肯定发生了什么
Something happened there.
对  但我们没办法调查
Yeah, but we have no way to investigate it.
等等
Wait.
也许我们可以
Maybe we do.
-可以吗  -看看这地方
- We do?  - Well, look at this place.
多美的天际啊
I mean, it's got beautiful skies,
一望无际的草场  老西部的刺激
Wide-open spaces, the thrill of the old west.
作为即兴蜜月行  有什么比这度假村更好的呢
What better place for an impromptu honeymoon?
当然  主要还是去调查案子
For the investigation, of course.
我们乘机几小时就可以到那里了
We could jump on a plane and be there in a few hours.
卡塞尔  你不会说真的吧
Castle, you cannot be serious.
我们一边度蜜月
We can find Whitney's killer
一边调查案子找出真凶  太完美了
and have a honeymoon at the same time -- it's perfect.
不  卡塞尔  我才不要去农场度蜜月呢
No, Castle. We are not having a honeymoon at a dude ranch!
这可是绝佳的掩护
Well, it -- then, it can be our cover story.
我们是一对渴望体验
We're a-a newlywed couple
狂野西部的新婚夫妇
with a hankerin' for the wild frontier, right?
听着  贝克特
And, look, Beckett,
我知道你想将
I know you want to see justice brought
凶手绳之以法
to this young woman's killer.
而这个
And this...
这是唯一的办法
This is the only way.
虽然不想承认  但也许你老公说的对
I hate to say this, but your husband may be right.
这可能是破案的最佳机会
This could be our best shot at solving the case.
好吧
Fine.
太棒了
Excellent.
备马吧亲爱的  因为我们要去西部度蜜月了
Saddle up, honey, because we are honeymooning out west.
有一种约翰·福特西部片的既视感
Wow. It's like we rolled right into a John Ford movie.
-谢谢  -好了  伙计
-Thank you. Okay, there, hoss.
记住我们是带着任务来的
Just remember we're here for a reason --
找到杀死惠特妮的凶手
To find Whitney's killer.
史上最棒的蜜月
Best honeymoon ever.
这可不是度蜜月
This is so not our honeymoon.
我想在旧西部  这是种吉兆
I think in the old west, that was a sign of good fortune.
太幸运了
Lucky me.
你们就是那对新人吧
Say, y'all must be the newlyweds!
两位  欢迎来到德蒙贝克老西部度假村
Well, welcome to the diamondback old west ranch, folks.
大家称呼我詹姆斯·格拉迪绅士
They call me gentleman James Grady,
我是这些楼房的业主
and I am the proprietor of this here establishment.
我叫里克  这位是凯特
I-I am Rick. This is Kate.
我想说  这个地方太棒了
And may I just say, this place is amazing.
是啊  原汁原味的
Yeah, very authentic.
这不正是你们这些游客慕名而来的吗
Oh, that's what you jackeroos came for, ain't it --
旧西部的传奇色彩  和浪漫
The legend and, dare I say, romance of the old west?
人手一份小册子
Now, uh, these brochures in your hands
详细介绍了我们提供的各项活动
detail all the activities that we have to offer here,
从骑牛到亲近自然
from cattle-driving to nature-walking.
我们都一应俱全
We got it all!
我们友善的度假村牛仔员工
And my friendly staff of ranch hands --
他们都戴红色三角巾
Uh, they're the ones in the red bandanas
小册子里都有  在这里
in the brochure and all around here --
他们会带领你们踏上心中渴望的冒险
They will guide you through any adventure your hearts desire.
可以开始了吗
So, shall we begin?
我们刚刚搭红眼航班过来
Actually, we jt got in on the red-eye
我们希望能先登记入住
and were kind of hoping to check in to our room.
没问题  因为你们是新婚
Hey, well, no problemo. Uh, seeing as you're newlyweds,
我将你们的房间升级到了酒店套房
I upgraded you to a suite in our grand hotel.
-真是太感谢了  -是啊  但是
- Oh, well, we're much obliged. - Uh, sure are. But...
我们想要一种更真实的体验
We were looking for a more authentic experience.
我们希望能够住在农舍房
And we're kind of hoping to stay at one of the bunkhouse rooms.
老婆说了算
Whatever the little lady wants.
我知道这个家谁做主了
I can see who wears the 10-gallon hat in your house.
格拉迪先生  我知道这听起来有点傻
Yeah. And, um, Mr. Grady, I know that this sounds silly,
但我的幸运数字是14  房间有人住吗
but my lucky number is 14 -- is that room available?
黛西·梅
Uh, Daisy Mae!
黛西·梅  你能过来一下吗
D-Daisy Mae, w-we need you, dear!
那是我老婆  和你家这位一样
That's my missus. Uh, like yours,
大小事都是她张罗的
she runs the show here.
亲爱的  这对璧人想要入住14号农舍房
Uh, hon, uh, these lovebirds want to stay in bunkhouse 14.
房间空着吗
Uh, is it vacant?
空着  为什么要住那间呢
Well, sure is, but why?
那是一张单人床单人房
It's a single room with a twin bed.
-没事的  我们抱着睡  -是啊
- Oh, that's okay. We're, uh -- we're cuddlers. - Yeah.
好吧  但是首先
Well, all righty, then. But first, folks,
我们得给你们换另一身打扮
we got to get you out of those bibs and tuckers.
瞧瞧这位
Take a look at this belvedere.
我看起来帅呆了  是吧
I do look good, don't I?
感觉像是三个幻想一起成真了
This is like three fantasies coming true all at once.
只是还缺了一样东西
Only thing missing is --
詹姆斯绅士  上哪弄像你这样的仿真枪呢
Gentleman James, where do we get the replica guns, like yours?
仿真  这里可是亚利桑那州
Replica? Son, this is Arizona.
可以配枪的
It's open-carry.
你们知道什么东西快过闪电吗
Say, do either of you two know what's quicker than lightning?
什么
What?
这把枪驯服了狂野西部
This gun tamed the wild west.
柯尔特点45单向决斗手枪
Colt .45 single-action peacemaker.
我长大后想成为和他一样的人
I want to be him when I grow up.
如果你长得大的话
Well, yeah, if you grow up.
熟能生巧
It's all about practice,
你可以用我们的枪练习
which you can do with one of our firearms
在我们的礼品店有卖
available for purchase at our gift shop.
我们现在就走吧
In fact, why don't we mosey on over?
格拉迪先生  下次再说吧
Yeah, uh, Mr. Grady, you know what? Maybe later.
我们现在都有点累了
Right now, we're both a bit knackered,
我们想先回房休息
so we were hoping to go to our room.
很高兴你住我们这里
So glad you're staying with us.
不胜感激  女士
Much obliged, ma'am.
我们错了
We were wrong.
这把钥匙和惠特妮身上的不是同一把
The key that Whitney had with her wasn't her room key.
那该怎么办
Well, then, what does it go to?
我不知道
I don't know.
14号房到了
Here's 14.
等等
Oh, wait.
不管喜不喜欢  我们都在度蜜月了
Whether we like it or not, we aron our honeymoon,
所以必须照规矩来
so we must act accordingly.
天啊
Oh! Geez!
是啊
Oh, yeah.
这才不是度蜜月呢
So not our honeymoon.
你在找消毒剂吗
Are you looking for disinfectant?
找线索  你忘了吗  惠特妮在这里住过
Clues. Remember? Whitney was staying here.
我觉得
I highly doubt
我们不会在这房间里找到任何线索
we're gonna find anything in this room that can help us.
你好  伙计
Howdy, partner.
不知道是不是房间随赠
I don't know if it comes with the room,
但有个裸体牛仔在我们的浴室里刮胡子
but there's a naked cowboy shaving in our bathroom.
抱歉  你说什么
I'm sorry, what?
怪我  忘了关门
My fault. Forgot to lock the door.
这是一个公共浴室
It's a jack-and-jill bathroom.
我是另一间房的房客
I'm in the room on the other side.
好吧  我叫里克  这位是凯特
Oh! Okay. Uh, I'm Rick. This is Kate.
我们刚刚入住  新婚夫妇
We, uh, just checked in. Newlyweds.
恭喜两位  我叫托拜厄斯
Oh, congratulations. I'm Tobias.
格拉迪先生刚才不是说
H-hi. Wait, didn't Mr. Grady say
这房间之前住过位女士吗
that there was a woman staying in our room before?
是啊
Uh, yes.
他们居然让她和男人住得这么近
I'm surprised they let her stay in so close with menfolk,
考虑到这里的老西部风俗
considering the customs of the old west.
我猜  当他们发现
Well, I guess when they found out
我和她一样都喜欢追求牛仔
me and her both enjoy chasing cowboys,
他们觉得"管他呢"
they figured, "What the heck?"
我们正准备泡咖啡
Uh, you know, we're about to brew some coffee.
你想来一杯吗
Would you care for a cup?
我对咖啡口味的喜好和对男人的一样
I like my coffee like I like my men --
强壮  肤黑  味苦
strong, black, and bitter.
你真有趣  我猜你和你之前的邻居
Ooh, you're fun! I bet you and your old bunkhouse mate
一定遇到过不少麻烦事
got into all sorts of trouble.
我可没有  不过惠特妮可不一样
Not me. But Whitney, on the other hand --
别误会我  她是个可人儿
Now, don't get me wrong. She's a sweetheart,
但她可不是个省油的灯
but she's a bit of a hell raiser.
-是吗  -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
-怎么说  -我们来这里的第一天
- How so? - Okay, like, our first day here,
我们去看一场马术表演
we went on a horseback-riding tour.
她中途偷偷溜走了
She snuck off in the middle of it.
真离谱  她去哪了
Get out. Where'd she go?
大概是去跟她那个牛仔员工鬼混去了吧
Probably went to go hang out with her ranch hand --
在这里工作的红巾男孩中的一个
One of the red-bandana boys that work here.
她会整晚和他在一起  每天如此
She used to stay out with him all night, every night.
听起来我最好让他离我夫人远一点
Sounds like I better keep him clear of my missus.
-这个罗密欧是谁  -我不知道  她不肯说
- Who was this Romeo? - I don't know. She wouldn't say.
她只说他很高很帅  黑皮肤
She just said he was tall, dark, and handsome...
而且有老婆
oh, and married.
有老婆吗  真离谱
Married?! Get out.
-没错  -不知道是不是出了什么麻烦
- Yes. - Ooh, I wonder if there was any trouble.
我们能住进这间屋子好像是
I kind of think the reason that we got this room
因为惠特妮提前离开了
is because Whitney left so early.
没错  昨天晚上
She sure did -- her last night here,
她凌晨三点才回来  心烦意乱的
she rolled in at 3:00 A.M., upset.
-她的哭声把我吵醒了  -发生什么事了
- She woke me up with all her crying. - What happened?
我也这样问她  可她不肯说
That's what I said, but she didn't want to talk about it.
天亮前她就离开了  连再见都没跟我说
She left before the sun came up. Didn't even say goodbye.
我约会要迟到了
Oh. I'm late for chow.
谢谢你们的咖啡  回头见
Thanks for the coffee. See y'all around.
好吧
Okay.
跟已婚男人的婚外情
An affair with a married man?
是的  凌晨三点之前她都跟他在一起
Yes, and she was with him until 3:00 A.M.
这正好是她被下毒的那段时间
that's right in the middle of her time-of-poisoning window.
-得找出这个人  -怎么找  我们是卧底
- We got to find this guy. - But how? We're undercover.
我不能就那么亮出警徽直接问别人
I can't just flash my badge and get people to talk.
没错  所以这次我们不能用警察的身份
Exactly, which is why we don't approach this like cops.
我们用作家的身份来打探消息
We approach this like writers.
我们拖到最后  然后编故事吗
So we procrastinate and make stuff up?
不是
No.
是  但也不是
Well, yes. But no.
在这个事情上
In this particular instance,
我们要像作家一样调查  那就是...
we approach the investigation like writers by...
做调研
doing research.
有七个牛仔员工符合
Now, there are seven ranch hands who fit the bill
高帅且黑的描述  但是为了找出
of tall, dark, and handsome, but in order to figure out
到底是哪个在跟惠特妮鬼混
which one was fooling around with Whitney,
我们必须先找出其中哪一个是已婚的
we have to first determine who of them are married.
所以我们找一下谁戴了婚戒
That means we need to go on a wedding-ring search.
这几个是可疑人物
And these are the possibilities.
我做了一下分工
So I split their classes up between us.
等一下
Whoa. Hold up.
口琴初学班  牛仔酒吧
Harmonica for beginners? Cowboy saloon?
为什么你分到的都是好地方
How come you get all the cool activities,
-而我分到的却是捆猪班  -因为是我的主意
- and I get hog-tying? - Because this was my idea.
尽管很可惜
Though it will be a shame
我们蜜月的第一天要分头行动了
that we're spending the first day of our honeymoon apart.
不可惜  因为这不是我们的蜜月旅行
Except we're not, because this is not our honeymoon.
好了  回见
Okay. Bye.
注意安全
Be safe.
莱恩  情况怎么样
Hey, Ryan, how's it going?
很好  我们刚讨论过你们的婚礼
Oh, wonderful. In fact, we were just discussing your nuptials.
不是实际的那场  因为我们都没参加
Not the actual event, since neither of us were there.
伙计们  你们就为了这事打电话吗
Guys, is this really why you're calling?
一部分原因是的
Partly, yes.
我们有新消息  先说好的
And we have news. Here's the good.
交通运输局监控显示惠特妮的包
MTA cameras show that Whitney's bags
的确遗落在了地铁站
were left on the subway.
坏消息是  包被一个流浪汉偷走了
Here's the bad news -- they were stolen by a homeless man.
不过我们发了全境通告
But we put out a BOLO.
希望有人会认出他来
Hopefully somebody will recognize him.
另外  蕾妮在尸检中也有所发现
Also, Lanie found something during her autopsy.
她在惠特妮的指甲里
She found traces of a wax-covered cardboard
和裤腰带中  发现了涂了蜡的纸屑
under Whitney's nails and on the waistband of her pants.
蜡纸屑  像包肉的那种纸吗
Wax-covered cardboard -- like butcher paper?
蕾妮说很难分辨
Lanie says it's too hard to tell.
你和跟屁虫那边怎么样  有发现吗
What about you and hop along? Learn anything?
目前看来  我们的死者
Uh, well, so far, it looks like our victim
在和一个已婚男人有婚外情
was having an affair with a married man.
不过问题是  男人的身份还是个谜
But the problem is, his identity is a mystery.
说到谜  我们跟惠特妮的朋友谈过
Well, speaking of mysteries, we spoke with Whitney's friends.
他们说在她出发之前
They said prior to her departure,
她花了很长时间待在历史协会
she was spending a good deal of time at the historical society.
他们知道她在那里干什么吗
Do they know what she was doing there?
我们还在调查  但是
Well, we're still looking into it, but --
好了  我要挂了
Okay, guys, I-I-I got to go.
凯特  你是要去捆猪班吗
Hey, Kate. Wait, are you going to hog-tying class?
-是的  -我也是
- Mm-hmm. Yeah. - Me, too.
天呐  我们一定会过得很愉快的
Oh, my god. We're gonna have so much fun!
是啊  一定会
Yeah, we sure are.
捆猪  好诶
Hog-tying. Yee-haw.
没有戒指
No ring.
排除一个
One down.
喝点什么  老兄
What'll it be, feller?
我要劣质威士忌酒
I'll take, uh, coffin varnish.
-什么  -就是暖肠酒
- What? - You know, gut-warmer.
[各种指威士忌的俚语]
Base burner. Nose paint. Cowboy cocktail.
你们这里管威士忌叫什么
What -- what do y'all call whiskey here?
威士忌
Whiskey.
先生  我需要你帮忙
Hey, mister. I sure could use your help.
我在找孔雀兄弟
I'm looking for the peacock boys.
我没见过他们  警官
Well, I haven't seen them, marshal,
但我会留神的[直译我会用一只眼盯着的]
but I'll, uh, keep an eye out.
你就打算站那看吗先生  还是来玩一局
You just gonna bat your eyes, mister, or you gonna play?
好的  我很爱玩
Oh, yeah. Hey, I'm a -- I'm a sporting man.
开始吧
There we go.
哥们儿  我注意到
Hey, there, partner, couldn't help but notice
你戴着个戒指啊
you got a ring on your finger.
我的才刚带上  新婚呢
Just had mine put on. Newlywed.
这不是戒指  这是绞绳
This isn't a ring. It's a noose.
这么惨啊
That bad, huh? Ooh.
我想也是啊  下半辈子
Yeah, I suppose, uh, one woman
都只和一个女人在一起确实不容易
for the rest of your life is a tall order.
-你有什么秘诀吗  -你会琢磨出来的
- What's your secret? - You'll figure it out.
好啦  说吧
Oh, come on. What --
你是还藏着个小情妇吗
do you got a little left-handed missus on the side?
我从不背叛我的妻子  朋友
I don't cheat on my wife, friend.
这和我听说的可有些出入啊
Well, that's, uh, not what I heard.
无耻的混蛋  你袖子里藏了个黑桃A
You no-good, mangy cur! You got an ace up your sleeve!
你知道出千都是怎么处理的吗  先生
You know what we do with card cheats in here, mister?!
等等  小子们  没听到铃声吗
Hold it, boys! Hear them bells?
正午了  这意味着好戏要上演
It's high noon. That means it's show time.
去后面解决  来一场传统的手枪决斗
Take it out back. Time for a good, old-fashioned gunfight.
你都知道了什么
What do you know?!
是我妻子派你来的吗
Huh? My wife send you?!
我从来没见过你妻子
Hey, I've never met your wife!
谁告诉你我有了外遇的
Who told you I was a cheater?!
惠特妮
Whitney did.
该死
Damn it!
我就知道  那女人跟你说的都是谎话
I knew it! Look, everything that woman said to you was a lie!
奥利  你搞什么啊
Ollie! What in tarnation?!
先生  你没事吧
Mister, are you okay?
你信以为真了吧
You thought that was real?
耶  奥利  击个掌
Yes, Ollie! Up high!
他  是你让他拽你出来的啊
He -- you asked him to throw you out?
是啊  西部风嘛
Yeah, like old-west style.
奥利演的可像呢
Ollie's been fantastic --
说什么咦嗬之类的
he's all "Yee-haw" and --
好吧
Well, all righty, then.
只要您玩的开心就行
As long as you're enjoying yourself.
我去
Damn.
差点就丢了工作
That could have cost me my job.
先生  我很抱歉
Look, mister, I'm sorry.
免了  你想让我保守秘密
Save it. You want my silence?
那就跟我讲讲惠特妮  你们俩怎么回事
Tell me about Whitney. What happened between you two?
是她找上我的
Look, she came on to me,
跟我调情  动手动脚的
started flirting, getting all handsy.
几个哥们儿见了  就说我们好上了
A bunch of the boys saw us and figured we hooked up,
但我们没有  我发誓
but we didn't -- I swear it.
事实上  我觉得她就是想要我的农场钥匙
In fact, I think she was just after my ranch key.
农场钥匙
Ranch key?
挂在一个蛇形钥匙链上
It's on a snake key chain.
我认为是她拉扯我的时候偷走了
I think she picked it off me when she was pawing at me.
-哪里的钥匙  -农场仓库
- What does the key open? - The ranch shed.
等等  你是说她偷了你的钥匙
Wait a minute. Y-you're saying that she stole your key
就为了进农场仓库
to open the ranch shed.
仓库里有什么
What's in the shed?
没什么  就是些农用工具
Nothing. Just ranch supplies.
我不明白
I don't get it.
惠特妮为什么要偷这里的钥匙呢
Why would Whitney steal the key to this place?
不知道  但显然这和外遇无关
I don't know. But clearly, it has nothing to do with the affair.
那她到底在找什么
Right, so what was she after?
卡塞尔  还记得蕾妮说
Castle, do you remember how Lanie said
她在惠特妮的指甲和腰带下
that she found traces of wax-covered cardboard
都发现有封蜡木箱的痕迹吗
under Whitney's nails and in her waistband?
记得  怎么了
Yeah, so?
你知道什么东西是装在封蜡木箱里的吗
So, you know what's wrapped in wax-covered cardboard?
炸药
Dynamite.
她进来是为了偷炸药
She broke in here to steal sticks of these.
农民用炸药清理田地
Ranchers use dynamite to clear their land.
惠特妮偷炸药又要干什么
What the hell was Whitney using it for?
知道惠特妮偷炸药想要做什么吗
Is there any indication why Whitney would steal dynamite?
还不知道  但卡塞尔和我
Not yet, but Castle and I
正在试图回顾她的每一步行动
have been re-tracing every move she made,
就从她开溜的那次骑马旅行开始
starting with that horseback-riding tour that she snuck away from.
-知道她去了哪吗  -我四处问了问
- Well, any idea where she was going? - I asked around,
她走的那条路好像是
and apparently, the trail that she took
通往印第安保留区的
led to the native American reservation.
等等  不是那个亚瓦佩保留区吧
Wait a minute -- it wasn't the Yavapai reservation, was it?
就是  你怎么知道的
Yeah. How'd you know?
历史协会
The historical society.
惠特妮查阅了18和19世纪时很生僻的
Whitney was looking up obscure documents and maps
一些地图和文件
from the late 18th, early 19th century.
大多数都是关于
Yeah, most of them had to do
亚瓦佩保留区附近的一个水坝工程
with the construction of a dam near the Yavapai reservation.
有人知道她为什么调查那里吗
Well, did anyone know why she was researching that area?
没  但那可能就是
No, but it's probably the
她去那里的原因
reason she went out there in the first place.
但这并没有解释为什么惠特妮需要炸药
But it doesn't explain why Whitney needed dynamite
或者她为什么会被毒杀
or why she was poisoned.
这一切肯定都有联系
Look, it's all got to be related.
卡塞尔和我正要去那个保留区
Castle and I are headed up to the reservation
寻找...线索
to get some answers... now.
两位  我得挂了
G-guys, I got to go.
你好啊
Hey, there!
贝克特  给你介绍一下
Beckett, meet the boys.
这匹叫埃斯波西托
This one's Esposito.
这匹小马就叫莱恩了  你准备好了吗
I'm calling the little one Ryan. Are you ready?
卡塞尔  我让你去找交通工具时
Uh, Castle, when I asked you to find us a ride,
我的想法是
I was thinking of something
类似于小货车之类的
more along the lines of a pickup truck.
保留区有20多公里远
The reservation's 15 miles away.
马车什么时候才能到啊
This is gonna take forever.
怎么跟你说呢
Yeah, well, what can I tell you?
这儿的一切都是正宗的西部风
Everything here's authentic old west.
真是的
Really?
无法抗拒是吗
Couldn't resist, huh?
非得搞一把六发式左轮手枪
Just had to get a six shooter.
是吧  很棒不是吗
Right? Isn't it great?
还有更赞的
And it gets better.
我也给你弄了一把  就当结婚礼物
I got you one, too. It's a wedding gift --
情侣套装
His-and-hers matching set.
谁说"我愿意"后  浪漫就走入坟墓来着
And who said romance dies after you say "I do"?
埃斯波西托  莱恩  驾
Esposito, Ryan!
不是吧  穿得像吉恩·奥特里片中的临时演员
Seriously, you're rolling up to the reservation
你们就跑到保留地了吗
dressed like extras from a Gene Autry movie?
有点太冒犯了吧
That's some real cultural insensitivity.
抱歉  先生  我们无意冒犯
Sorry, sir. We didn't mean any offense.
我们在德蒙贝克度假
We're -- we're vacationing at Diamondback.
我看出来了
Yeah, I figured that.
我只是逗你们玩
I was just messing with you folks.
放轻松
Relax.
他骗到我了
He got me. Yeah.
欢迎
Welcome.
我叫里克
Yeah. Well, I'm Rick.
-好的  -这位是凯特
- Yes. - This here is Kate.
我们正在度蜜月
And we... are on our honeymoon.
-不是吗  宝贝  -当然
- Ain't we, honey? - Yeah. We sure are.
我们在德蒙贝克遇到个客人
Um, so, we met a guest at Diamondback.
她的名字叫惠特妮
Her name was Whitney.
她说她来这时
She said that she came out here,
发现了令人惊叹的景象
and she discovered some breathtaking views.
当然  我记得惠特妮  是个好姑娘
Yeah, sure. I remember Whitney. Nice girl.
几天前她骑着一匹阿帕卢萨马来到这
She came out a few days ago riding an appaloosa.
但她对风光可不感兴趣
But she wasn't interested in the scenery.
真的吗  她对什么感兴趣呢
Really? What was she, uh, interested in?
和炸药有关系吗
Did it have anything to do with dynamite?
炸药吗  不是的
Dynamite? No.
她只是对一个亚瓦佩词有疑问
She just had a question about a yavapai word.
-什么词  -Aha gah hel'lah
- What word was that? - Aha gah hel'lah.
她想知道这个词有没有歧义
She wanted to know if it could be misinterpreted.
-像是个奇怪的问题  -不
- Seems an odd question. - Not really.
我们许多词的词义会根据语境而改变
Many of our words change depending on the context.
Aha gah hel'lah的意思是河流
Aha gah hel'lah means "River,"
但有时也表示小溪
but sometimes, it means "Stream."
为什么她想知道那个词的意思呢
Why would she want to know about that word?
我不清楚
I have no idea.
但是听到我的答案惠特妮很高兴
But Whitney was happy with my answer.
谢过我之后她就走了
She thanked me and left.
就这样吗  我没明白
And that was it? I don't get it.
我也不太明白为什么
Yeah, well, I don't get
新婚夫妇穿得像牛仔一样来度蜜月
newlyweds dressing up like cowboys on their honeymoon,
但我还是不多说了
but I try not to judge.
关于惠特妮我们知道的越多
You know, the more we learn about Whitney,
我越发不明白她要干什么
the less I understand about what she was up to.
是啊  历史协会
Yeah, I mean, the historical society,
亚瓦佩词语  炸药
the yavapai word, the dynamite --
这些为什么会让人下毒害死惠特妮呢
How does all of that add up to someone poisoning whitney?
这都说不通啊
It just doesn't make sense.
你知道吗  还有些事也说不通
You know what else doesn't make any sense
那就是我们虽然结了婚
is we're married, and...
但一点儿也不像结了婚的样子
we're not acting like it.
你有什么想法  牛仔
What do you got in mind, cowboy?
承认吧  你被我的才华闪瞎了
Admit it. You're impressed.
是啊  的确
Yeah, you're right. I am.
事实上  这挺奇妙的
This is actually... kinda magical.
为我们  为这趟旅程  还有将来干杯
To us, to the journey, and to what lies ahead.
怎么啦
What?
你知道吗
You know...
或许这可以成为我们的蜜月
Maybe this is our honeymoon.
卡塞尔  别动
Castle, don't move.
你的愿望就是我的命令
Your wish is my command.
不  我是认真的  一步都别动
No, I'm serious. Don't move an inch.
不要
Oh. No!
不不  不要
No, no, no, no, no.
埃斯波  莱恩  回来
Espo, Ryan, come back!
伙计们  不  回来
Guys! No, come back!
你之前说得对
Well, you were right before.
这完全不是我们的蜜月
This is so not our honeymoon.
谢天谢地
Well, thank goodness.
我们正准备派一队人马
We were fixing to put together a posse
去找你们俩呢
to go searching for the two of you.
对不起  格拉迪先生
Yeah, sorry, Mr. Grady.
我们想给你打电话的
We tried to call you,
但山里头没信号
but we couldn't get a signal in the hills.
你们的马几小时前就回来了  怎么了
Your horses came back hours ago. What happened up there?
我们遇到了和你的度假村同名的东西
We met a namesake of your ranch.
响尾蛇  好吧
Oh, a rattler. Yeah.
你们回酒吧
Well, why don't you mosey on over to the cantina
吃点东西  再喝点新鲜果汁
and strap on a feed bag and get some fresh jitter juice in you?
我们会的
Yeah, I think we'll do that.
换上干净的衣服我们马上就去
Yeah, just as soon as we get on some fresh union suits.
你们找到被害人的行李箱了吗
You found our victim's suitcases?
是的  长官  全境通告发出后
Yes, sir -- our B.O.L.O. got a hit
得以找到在地铁被流浪汉拿走的箱子
on the homeless guy who took them from the subway.
里面是惠特妮做的调查
Inside is Whitney's research
还有我们之前没见过的东西  一封信
and something we haven't seen before -- a letter.
没有寄件人地址
There was no return address,
但上面有一个亚利桑那州1992年的邮戳
but it's got an Arizona postmark dated 1992.
20年前的信
A 20-year-old letter?
小竹竿  由瑞贝卡·杜林转交
"Slim, in care of Rebecca Doolin."
-寄到新泽西  -希望找到杜林女士
- Jersey address. - Yeah, we're hoping to track down Ms. Doolin
我们就能找到一些答案
so we can get some answers.
这封信是个名叫克莱德的人写的
The letter's from a guy named Clyde.
我们认为照片上的人就是他
We assume that the photograph is him.
这里说克莱德是德蒙贝克的一个季节工
It says here that Clyde was a seasonal worker at Diamondback.
20年前  那还不是个度假村
Yeah, 20 years ago, before the place was a resort.
但有趣的是
But here's the interesting part.
信上克莱德不停地讲
In the letter, Clyde goes on about
他和一个名叫杜奇的人
how he and a guy named Dutch
即将揭开一个大秘密
were close to figuring out some big secret.
什么大秘密
What big secret?
信上没有说  但克莱德写道
It doesn't say, but Clyde wrote,
我只需要再多几周  小竹竿
"I just need a few more weeks.
杜奇和我已经很接近了
"Slim, Dutch, and I are so close.
全都是因为一个亚瓦佩词
"It all comes down to a mistranslation
-理解错误  -让我猜猜
- of a Yavapai word." - Let me guess.
-Aha gah hel'lah  -是的  你怎么知道
- Aha gah hel'lah. - Yeah, how'd you know?
这和惠特妮问亚瓦佩长老的是同一个词
It's the same word Whitney was asking the Yavapai elder about.
克莱德接下去是这么写的
Well, Clyde goes on to write,
"我无法相信一个不起眼的古老词汇"
"I can hardly believe that one little, old word"
"竟然是解开孔雀兄弟秘密的关键"
"is the key to the secret of the Peacock boys."
"等我找到了宝藏  我就回家找你"
"As soon as I find it, I'm coming on home to you."
"爱你  克莱德"
"Love, Clyde."
孔雀兄弟  哪里听过似的...
The Peacock boys -- how do I know...
他们是那对通缉犯
They're wanted men.
科尼利厄斯和珀西·孔
Cornelius and Percy Pea...
雀
...cock.
莱恩  你知道信里提到那些人是谁吗
Hey, Ryan, any idea who those people in the letter are?
不  哈维正在调查这位收件女士的下落
No, but Javi's trying to track down the lady who the letter was sent to.
我会及时通知你的
I'll keep you posted.
对  知通  及时
Yes, posted. K-keep --
通知  及  及时  及时通...
Post-- keep -- keep -- keep us po--
谢谢  多谢  莱恩
Thank you. Thank you, Ryan.
口水快擦擦  牛仔
Eyes back in their sockets, cowboy.
-还有个谋杀案要破呢  -说的对
- We got a murder to solve. - Right.
这个叫克莱德的是什么人
Now, who is this Clyde fellow,
为什么被害人会有他的信件
and why did our victim have his letter?
这些又和孔雀兄弟有什么关系
And what does any of this have to do with the Peacock boys?
好问题  我知道谁能回答这些问题
Good questions. And I know who has the answers.
真的
You do?
西部片里只有他才能解答你的所有问题
The same person who always has the answers in westerns --
可亲可爱  无所不知的酒保
The affable, all-knowing barkeep.
火车大盗
Train robbers.
1893年抢了一列南太平洋公司的火车
Held up the Southern Pacific back in 1893.
卷走了50块美国财政部金砖
Made off with 50 bars of US Treasury gold.
金子
Gold?
24K纯金  伙计
24-karat Au, feller.
孔雀兄弟穿过了亡者峡谷
Them Peacock boys -- they outrun a whole squad of soldiers
甩掉了一整队士兵
by traversing Deadman's Gorge.
两天之后  他们在菲尼克斯城外被击毙
Two days later, they was gunned down just outside of Phoenix.
但金子却不见了
But the gold was gone.
金子的事难道没有人知道吗
And no one knows anything about it?
有不少传闻
There were rumors.
1947年  传教士开始写下
1947, the missionaries started writing down
关于亚瓦佩人的古老故事
the old stories of the Yavapai people.
其中一个故事讲得是黑狐
One of them was about black fox --
一小孩  讲他被孔雀兄弟绑架后
Just a kid, abducted by them Peacock boys.
被迫做他们的向导
Forced him to be their guide.
他们在旅途中停了下来
But during their journey, they stopped,
他们把可怜的黑狐绑在一棵树上
and they tied poor black fox to a tree,
就在河的南岸
just south of the river,
他们驾着装满黄金的马车离开了
and they rode off in their gold-laden wagon.
他们回来之后
But when they returned...
黄金不见了
It was empty.
孔雀兄弟把金子藏了起来
The Peacock brothers stashed the gold.
其他人也都这么觉得
That's what everybody thought.
这个故事流传开后  寻宝猎人就...
When this story surfaced, treasure hunters --
纷涌而至
they came a-coming.
-有人找到了吗  -没有
- Anybody ever find it? - Nope.
所以这成为了西部的又一个传奇
And that's why this is just another legend of the old west.
惠特妮是在找这些金子
Whitney was after the gold.
假如传教士在编写黑狐的故事的时候
What if, when those missionaries wrote down black fox's story,
他们把某些地方弄错了
they wrote it down incorrectly?
那个亚瓦佩词有两个意思  记得吗
That Yavapai word has two meanings, remember?
假如孔雀兄弟并没有把金子藏在河边
What if the Peacocks didn't stash the gold near a river?
假如他们是把金子藏在了小溪边
What if they stashed it near a stream?
卡塞尔
Castle,
快看这些惠特妮研究的地图
look at these maps from Whitney's research.
1893年时河北边还有条小溪流
In 1893, there was a small stream north of the river.
到了1920年因为修坝断流了
And then, in 1920, it was dammed off.
等等  也就是说这么多年
Wait, that means all those years,
大家找金子的地方
everyone was looking for the gold
-都错了  -都错了
- In the wrong place. - In the wrong place!
那也正是惠特妮需要炸药的原因
That's why Whitney needed the dynamite,
她要炸开藏金子的地方
to blast open whatever hiding place it was in.
发现50块金砖后  你会怎么办呢
But what do you do when you discover 50 bars of gold,
放在行李箱里飞回家吗
fly it home in your carry-on?
当然不是  于是她把金子留在这
'course not. So she left it there.
然后回到纽约寻求帮助
She went back to New York for help.
大概是凶手发现了她的秘密
But perhaps the killer caught on to her,
下毒杀她灭口
poisoned her to silence her
这样就能把那些金子据为己有
and to keep the gold for themselves.
惠特妮回家的时候  她很烦躁
When Whitney went home, she was upset.
那像是刚发现金子的人的表现吗
Does that sound like someone who'd just found gold?
好吧
Okay.
你难倒我了
Mm, you got me there.
但如果惠特妮是在找金子的话
But if Whitney was searching for the gold
凶手跟踪了她  那一定会有线索的
and the killer tracked her, there could be clues.
你一直在假设那些金子还在那里
You keep assuming that the gold's still out there.
别忘了  克莱德和杜奇以前也在找
Don't forget, Clyde and Dutch were looking for it.
他们也许已经找到了
They might have found it.
不会的  他们可没有惠特妮的那些老地图
Not if they didn't have those old maps that Whitney had.
你一心只想找那些金子
You just want to go after the gold.
我当然想找金子了  那可是金子啊
Of course I want to go after the gold! It's gold!
好吧  听着
Okay, look.
如果我们利用惠特妮的研究
If we use Whitney's research,
我们就有可能找到杀害惠特妮的凶手
we may find Whitney's killer, too.
拜托  贝克特  你说怎样
Come on, Beckett. What do you say?
没错  这是我
Yeah, that's me.
不过我已经不住在那里好些年了
But I haven't lived at this address in years.
瑞贝卡  谁是小竹竿
Rebecca, who is Slim?
她是我的一个朋友
She was a friend of mine.
她的真名是弗吉尼亚·威廉姆斯
Her real name's Virginia Williams.
她是有个女儿叫惠特妮吗
Wait, did she have a daughter named Whitney?
弗吉尼亚和我住在一起的时候正怀着惠特妮
Well, Virginia was pregnant with Whitney when she stayed with me.
-那会儿弗吉尼亚真是一团糟  -怎讲
- Virginia was a real mess back then. - How so?
怀着孕  没有钱  没有未来
Knocked up, no money, no prospects.
弗吉尼亚受够了收到类似这样的信件
Virginia got so fed up with getting letters like these,
她终于给克莱德写了绝交信
She finally wrote Clyde a "Dear John" letter
决定向前看了
and moved on.
-你是说克莱德是惠特妮的父亲  -没错
- Wait, are you saying that Clyde is Whitney's father? - Mm-hmm.
你知道克莱德现在在哪里吗
Do you have any idea where Clyde is now?
都20年了  我怎么知道
It's been 20 years. How would I know?
惠特妮一定是在母亲去世之后找到了克莱德的信
Whitney must have found Clyde's letters after her mother passed.
是的  然后便开始了她的寻宝之旅
Yeah, and that's what started her quest.
根据这张地图
Now, according to the map.
那条溪流应该就在这一带
The stream used to be right around here...
我想是吧
I think.
也许吧
Maybe.
我不知道
I-I don't know.
卡塞尔  你干吗呢
Castle, what are you doing?
我在追踪惠特妮寻金的脚步
I am tracking Whitney's path to the gold.
怎么个追踪法
And how are you doing that?
盯着地面看啊
By staring at the dirt.
所有老的西部片里都这么演
That's how they do it in all the old Westerns.
是  但人家是牛仔  你是个纽约客
Yes, because they're cowboys. You're a New Yorker.
-东部人  都市人  -没错
- An Easterner. A city slicker. - Yes.
正因为我是都市人  所以我可以
And because I'm a city slicker, I can tell you,
百分百确定地告诉你  惠特妮到过这
with absolute certainty, Whitney was here.
你怎么知道  你又不会凭脚印追踪
How? You don't know how to read tracks.
我是不会  但正因为我是纽约人
No, no, but because I'm a New Yorker,
我知道怎么凭垃圾追踪
I know how to read litter.
你看这个
Check this out.
烧焦的打蜡纸板
Charred wax-covered cardboard.
惠特妮肯定在附近引爆了炸药
Whitney must have detonated the dynamite nearby.
咱们接近了
We're close.
那里更多
Ah. More there.
贝克特  看啊
Beckett, look at this.
还真是有金子啊
There's gold in them Thar Hills.
你先下去  看看有没有蛇
You go first. Check for snakes.
这地方真古老啊
This place is old!
这个矿肯定在孔雀兄弟藏金前
This mine must have been abandoned
就已经被遗弃了
before the Peacock boys stashed their loot.
慢点走  卡塞尔
Slow down, Castle.
-小心点  -开什么玩笑
- Just be careful. - Are you kidding?
这里可有宝藏  惠特妮找到了金子
There's treasure in here. Whitney found the gold.
又或者克莱德找到了金子  跟他的哥们杜奇分了
Or Clyde found the gold and split it with his buddy Dutch
然后抛弃了惠特妮母女
and simply abandoned Whitney and her mom.
我绝对确定克莱德没有找到金子
I'm absolutely positive Clyde didn't find the gold.
你怎么能这么确定呢
And how can you be so sure, huh?
因为金子还在
Because it's still here.
一个多世纪以来  50块金条
For over a century, 50 ingots of pure gold
一直被困在这个阴冷的墓穴中
have been trapped in this cold, dark tomb,
耐心地等待救援
waiting patiently to be rescued.
你听见了吗  贝克特
You hear that, Beckett?
你听见它们的呼唤了吗
Do you hear them calling?
它们在召唤我
Calling to me.
你的等待结束了  我的金子朋友
Your wait is over, my golden friends.
我来救你们了
I'm here to save you.
好吧
Okay!
这可不是金子
That's not gold!
-这是钝器外伤  -没错  而且凭这顶帽子
- That's blunt-force trauma. - Yep. And given this hat,
我就猜到死者是谁了
I'm pretty sure I know who the victim is.
-是克莱德  -没错
- It's Clyde. - Yep.
卡塞尔  你觉得
Castle, do you think
惠特妮是不是来这找她父亲的呢
that Whitney came out here to find her dad?
这就能解释她离开时为什么那么难过了
Well, that explains why she was so upset when she left.
你猜的对  克莱德多年前就找到了宝藏
You were right. Clyde found the treasure years ago.
是  但他哥们杜奇摆了他一道
Yeah, but then his buddy Dutch double-crossed him.
杜奇自己独吞了金子
Dutch took the gold for himself,
把他的血衣丢下了
left his blood-stained shirt behind.
如果他已经杀过一次人了  那他为了
And if he killed once, what's to stop him
保护自己的秘密就会不惜代价再开杀戒
from killing again to protect his secret?
等会  如果惠特妮找到了她被害的父亲
Wait, if Whitney found her murdered father,
那她何不直接去找警长呢
why not just go straight to the sheriff?
为什么要坐第一班飞机回家呢
Why take the first flight home?
去找杀害她父亲的凶手对质  杜奇只是他的绰号
To confront her father's killer. Dutch was just his nickname.
卡塞尔  看  这件衬衣上有干洗店的标签
Castle, look. There's a laundry tag on this shirt.
上面有姓名缩写P.D.
It has the initials "P.D."
菲利普·达格玛
Philip Dagmar.
我和惠特妮的死一点关系也没有
I had nothing to do with Whitney's death.
你确定吗  达格玛先生
Are you sure about that, Mr. Dagmar...
还是说你更喜欢我们叫你杜奇
or should we call you Dutch?
我们查过你的通话记录
We checked your phone records.
在惠特妮被害那天早上  你接到过一个
There was a call from the ranch pay phone
从牧场的公用电话打来的电话
to your cellphone the morning of Whitney's murder.
她打过电话给你  对吧
She called you, didn't she?
她说了什么
What did she say?
说她要飞回家
That she was flying home,
还说她要当面跟我谈谈
and she needed to speak with me in person.
你之前为什么不告诉我们
Why didn't you tell us this before?
-因为这会使我有嫌疑  -没错  的确如此
- Because it makes me look guilty. - You're right. It does.
我敢说你在那个小镇里
I bet you've still got connections
仍有人脉  对吧
in that one-horse town, don't you?
我为什么要杀惠特妮
Why would I kill Whitney?
因为她发现了你的秘密  杜奇
Because she knew about your secret, Dutch.
我们找到了克莱德的尸骨
We found Clyde's skeleton.
当年你拿走那50块金条时丢下的尸骨
The skeleton that you left when you took those 50 bars of gold.
你们是说关于孔雀兄弟
So you're saying that the story
和金子的故事是真的吗
about the Peacock boys and the gold is true?
没错  还有人因此丧了命
Yeah, and someone found out the hard way.
这对生意可不利
Well, that's not gonna be good for business.
你不用担心
Now, don't you worry none.
早在你们买下这里以前就有这个传说了
All that nonsense is from long before y'all bought the place.
不会有人被吓跑的  我会确保这点的
It's not gonna scare anyone off. And I'll make sure of it.
谢谢你了  警长
We appreciate that, sheriff.
吉米我要借用一下牧场的全地形车
Jimmy, I sure could use the ranch's ATVs
去一下那个矿井
to get up to this mine.
没问题  我们有两辆呢  你都拿去用吧
'Course. We got two of them. They're all yours.
走吧  我带你过去
Come on. I'll take you to them.
警探  可以请你给我带路吗
Detective, would you mind showing me the way?
没问题
Not a problem.
我不在你要乖乖的  卡塞尔
Try to stay out of trouble while I'm gone, Castle.
那还有什么意思
Where's the fun in that?
听起来你过得很精彩啊  孩子
Sounds like you had a hell of a day, son.
想不想坐下来给我讲讲
Want to bend an elbow and tell me all about it?
酒我请
Drinks are on me.
这些年来我已经为惠特妮尽力了
I did the best I could for Whitney all these years.
但她还是想知道她父亲的下落
But she wanted to find out what happened to her father.
天啊  我真不敢相信她找到他了
God, I can't believe she found him.
她找到父亲后  你知道要做什么  对吧
And when she did, you knew exactly what to do, didn't you?
于是你雇人给她下毒
So you hired someone to poison her.
不  我没杀惠特妮
No, I-I didn't kill Whitney.
-但我知道是谁干的  -少来  杜奇  我们知道是你
- But I think I know who did. - Come on, Dutch. We know it was you.
我和克莱德找不到那条小溪的所在地
Clyde and I couldn't find the location of the old stream.
于是我们找了个在镇里长大的人帮忙
So we enlisted the help of someone who grew up in the town.
我和克莱德计划找到金子后就上交国库
Clyde and I planned to turn in the gold
然后领取发现者奖金
and collect the finder's fee from the treasury.
但是我们的新同伙不同意
But our new partner disagreed.
他们打了起来
They fought,
然后克莱德跌倒  摔在一块石头上
and then Clyde fell, landed on a rock,
撞到了头
and hit his head.
几分钟内他就死了
He was dead in minutes.
那就是我出卖灵魂的时候
That's when I sold my soul...
为了25块金条
For 25 bars of gold.
达格玛先生  你的另外一位同伙是谁
Mr. Dagmar, who was your other partner?
好酒
Smooth.
不好意思  接个电话
Excuse me.
莱恩  老西部没有手机
Ryan, they didn't have mobile phone in the old west,
你影响到了这里的气氛和我的酒兴
so you're kind of killing the vibe and my buzz.
听着  贝克特跟你在一起吗
Listen, is Beckett with you?
没有  怎么了
No. Why?
我一直给她打电话发短信  她没接
I've been calling and texting. She's not answering.
她在车上
She's on a ATV.
她可能听不见电话  怎么了
She probably can't hear her phone. What's up?
还有一个同伙  他才是凶手
There was a third partner. He's the killer.
警长吗
The sheriff?
不  是詹姆斯·格拉迪
No, it's James Grady.
看来我们该告别了
Well, I guess this is goodbye.
格拉迪  站住
Grady, stop.
谁能阻止我  你吗
Who's gonna make me, son? You?
听着  格拉迪  你
L-look, Grady, you, uh...
你杀了我  那你头上的凶案
You'll kill me, that's just another murder
又多了一桩
you're gonna have to answer for.
如果我先赶到墨西哥就不会
Not if I make it to Mexico first.
我不能让你跑掉
I can't let that happen.
算你有种  孩子  这我得承认
You got sand, boy. I'll give you that much.
你为何不坐下  再喝一杯呢
Why don't you just sit on down and have another drink?
我说孩子
Come on, son.
想想你的妻子
think of your wife.
正想着呢
I am.
好吧
Fine.
如果你非要
If you got a hankering for a residence
找死
in the bone orchard,
我成全你
I'll accommodate you.
有遗言吗
Any last words?
有
Yeah.
如果我活下来
If I survive this...
我要在大众点评上给这地方恶评
I'm giving this place a scathing review on yelp.
看来你看到莱恩的短讯了
I, uh -- I guess you got Ryan's message.
卡塞尔  我走开五分钟
Castle, I leave you alone for five minutes,
你就跟人单挑上了
and you end up in a showdown?
是的
Yeah, well...
好在我娶了东方最快女枪手
Good thing I married the, uh, fastest gun from the east.
惠特妮是用自己名字入住的
Given that Whitney checked in under her own name,
格拉迪估计从她来到这里就盯上她了
Grady may have been onto her from the moment she arrived.
或许没用多久就查明了她的来意
Probably didn't take him long to figure out why she came.
知晓之后  他跟着她来到矿厂
And when he did, he must have followed her to the mine
-看到了她的发现  -是的  她来的那天早上
- and seen what she discovered. - Yep. On the morning she left,
格拉迪在网上特意查了毛地黄下毒
Grady made specific internet searches on foxglove poisoning.
看来证据确凿啊  警长
Sounds like you got him dead to rights, sheriff.
加上你们的帮忙  是这样
Well, with what you did here, we sure do.
探长  我欠你人情
Detective, I'm in your debt.
保重
Y'all take care of yourselves.
谢了  警长
Thank you, sheriff.
看来我们为这个镇除了害
Well, I guess we cleaned up this town.
是的
Yeah, I reckon we did.
该回家了
So guess it's, uh, time to go home.
不  但你知道最让我痛心的是什么吗
No, no, but, well, you know what really gets me
他们说只邀请了家人
is that they said they only invited immediate family.
怎么  我们不是家人吗
What? We're not family?
更像是被嫌弃的亲戚
More like poor relations.
再说他们相爱
And we're probably the reason
-多半是因为我们  -可不是
- that they fell in love in the first place. - Right?
我听你们抱怨了
You know, I've been listening to your bellyaching
好几天了  我不得不问
for the last few days, and I have to ask --
你俩脑袋被门挤了吗
What the hell's wrong with you two?
长官  难道这事一点都不困扰你吗
Come on, sir. It doesn't bother you?
你真的想知道我的看法吗  警探
You really want to know what I think, detectives?
我觉得你们应该停止抱怨
I think that the two of you should stop whining
不要搞得像小女孩没被邀请参加舞会一样
like two little schoolgirls who weren't invited to the dance
祝福你们的好友
and be happy that your friends, your very dear friends,
他们找到了办法走到一起
have found a way to make it work,
尤其是考虑到他们经历的一切
especially after all the hell those two have been through.
总之  我是这么想的
Now, that's what I think.
你这么一说
Well, when you put it that way...
是的  在某些人看来
Yeah, I mean, I guess in some opinions,
-我俩对这事是挺犯浑的  -是的
- We have been kind of jerks about it. - I guess.
没错
Yeah. You have.
不过如果你们感兴趣
But if you're interested,
你们还是能够弥补他们的
there might be something you could do to make it up to them.
里克  看到你们走我好难过
Well, Rick, sorry to see you guys go.
我也是  但是没办法
Oh, yeah, me, too, but, uh, it couldn't be helped.
嗨  牛仔
Hey, there, cowboy.
这么急要去哪儿啊
Where you off to in such a hurry?
贝克特  你在干什么
Beckett, what are you doing?
我们会错过航班的
We're gonna miss our flight.
你早上就得到分局
You got to be in the office by morning.
-不用  -怎么不用
- No, I don't. - Yeah, you do.
-你没有可用假期了  -事实上  我有
- You don't have any personal days left. - Actually, I kind of do.
作为结婚礼物  莱恩和埃斯波西托
For our wedding gift, Ryan and Esposito
各自腾出一个假期给了我
have both agreed to give me two of their vacation days each.
-是吗  -是的
- They did? - Yeah.
现在我们有四天
So, now we have four days
想做什么  就做什么
to do whatever...we...want.
你想留在这
And you want to stay here?
当然
Of course I want to stay.
毕竟  这是我们的蜜月
After all, this is our honeymoon.
等等  我们还是会去岛上度假吧
Oh, wait. We're gonna still go to that island getaway, right?
-当然  -那就好
- Yes. Absolutely. - Okay, good.